the square pyramidal numbers represent
the number of unit cubes in a pyramid of
stacked Square arrays with sides of
length one up to n for instance this
diagram shows the 24th square pyramidal
number because the bottom square has
side length 24 and the top square has
side length 1 it turns out that this
particular square pyramidal number 4900
is special other than the trivial
Solutions of 0 and 1 it is the only such
number that can also be arranged in one
large Square array we can lay down the
square array levels like this only
splitting up the 4x4 and the 6x6 squares
to fill gaps once we've done this we
have an entire 70x 70 square filled in
thus 4900 is the only non-trivial
solution to the so-called Cannonball
problem which asks for numbers that are
simultaneously square pyramidal and
square